Chitrank Dixit

Software Engineer

+919769730095 | chitrankdixit@gmail.com | 2305, Sudama Nagar D 301 Indore (M.P.) |

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineer with 6+ years experience developing web applications with startups.

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End	CSS3, Bootstrap, HTML5, JavaScript, React.js, Angular.js.	
Back End	Python, Django, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Sails, Spring, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra.	
Data Stores	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch, Aerospike, Google Cloud Datastore.	
Web Servers	Nginx, Google Web Server, Gunicorn.	
Operating Systems	Ubuntu, Mac OS X.	
Cloud Platform	AWS, AWS Lambda, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform	

EXPERIENCE

Senior Python Developer | YouGov | Mumbai, India

Jul 2019 - Present

YouGov

YouGov is a British international Internet-based market research and data analytics firm, headquartered in the UK, with operations in Europe, North America, the Middle East and Asia-Pacific.

YouGov Oauth Server and Client

- Created an Oauth 2.0 Server for YouGov.
- Documenting Oauth flow (Authorization Code with PKCE).
- Design UML diagrams for the Authorization Code with PKCE flow.
- Enabled Authorization Code with PKCE.
- Created Client to consume token and get user data from Oauth clients (Google, Facebook, In House YouGov provider).
- Unit Tests and Integration Tests.
- Kubernetes Deployment.

YouGov Capn (Survey System Team)

• Enabled Sqlalchemy ORM for Survey System Data APIs.

- Generated weekly reports for PII variables usage.
- Kubernetes Deployment for Capn

YouGov Perfil (writing survey results)

- Enabled Autoscaling based on Memory Utilization.
- Enabled Newrelic distributed tracing for better error trace.

YouGov Kuest (viewing the questionnaires)

- Enabled Newrelic distributed tracing for better error trace.
- Add API to view questionnaires with specific versions.

YouGov Datum (Survey Systems Team)

- Change controls workflow: worked on API and UI for workflows when existing survey questions get edited.
- Notifications Pipeline when survey common questions changed or changes got approved.
- Global Data Definitions: Created a subset of data out of questions for newer and more extensive UI features.

Software Engineer | Turtlemint | Mumbai, India

Jul 2018 - Jul 2019

Turtlemint is Web Aggregator for various Insurers, It allows organizations and customers to choose the relevant insurance as their needs. It has Motor, Health, Term, Non-Term Insurance categories to choose from.

Term and Non-Term Integration

- Design and Analysed the flow of Term Insurance Application in Non-Term Application.
- Updated the Age, Premium, Policy Premium Term validators for Term Insurance flow.
- Redirection Url generation flow for Insurers.

Notification Service and Authentication Service Logging

Added Bunyan rotation based Logging into notification service.

SMS and Email Tasks

- Designed the flow for url shortening service.
- Add CC, BCC mailing feature while sending emails.

Partner Management and MIS

- Design and Model service to store the partner and sell policies records.
- Import and export partner and policy details service using Aws Lambda.

Ninja Analytics Team

- Deciding on the data to be saved for policy issuance and policy detail flow.
- Create or update APIs data Role based based user.
- Create or update historical data for the updations made.

Dockerizing Services

- Dockerize lead service project for better deployments in future.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Java Spring Boot, Python, Python Flask, AWS Lambda, Nodejs, Expressjs, sails, Mongo, Nginx, Aerospike, Docker.

Software Engineer | Happay | Bengaluru, India

Mar 2018 - Jul 2018

Happay is an advanced expense management system for organizations. It allows organizations to choose their custom

settings using workflows and control the expense flow system. It also allows food, travel and accommodation listing and booking from its platform.

Travel Convenience Fee Structure

- Data Modelling to store and manage Organization and their convenience fee plan.
- APIs for Creating, Reading, Updating and Deleting the Travel Convenience configuration.
- Written a Service that would take the parameter based on that the Service would decide the Travel Convenience Fee for a Flight or a Hotel and progressive discount for every additional person.

Flight Status App

- Data Modelling to store and manage Flight status app users their listed and booked flights.
- Creating Session Authentication flow for the User who comes to the app.
- Integrating Third Party APIs into Happay system to get Flights Data for any date, source and destination.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Python, Django, Postgresql, Nginx, Celery, Gunicorn, postman, uWSGI, AWS

Backend Developer | Flyrobe | Mumbai, India

Dec 2015 - Mar 2018

Flyrobe is India's biggest fashion rental service. It offers renting western and ethnic clothing with customized sizes that fits the customer. On the other hand Flyrobe US offers buying the ethnic customized clothing.

Web Application

- Dealing with the real time queries of Flyrobe Operation (Order Management and Cataloging)
- Google Cloud Messaging integration to send push notifications to the user.
- Created Coupons for various campaigns and in collaborations with various companies (like Ola, etc).
- Worked on Current Order, Past Order, Product Listing, Product Detail, Shopping Cart (CRUD), Order Create, Order Status Change, Offers and Packages, Invoice and Order Track, Apply Coupon, Wishlist (CRUD), Address (CRUD) APIs.
- Restructuring Flyrobe Backend , improving and enhancing Database Design for faster Data Flow.
- Worked on Measurement Slot Booking flow, in which Users can select a slot when they want to give their measurement to the fitting expert.
- Worked on Product List API served with Elasticsearch data for querying and filtering over the dataset.

Merchant Management System

- Data Modelling for Storing Merchant, Merchant Payments, Merchant Consignment and Item Consignment Details, updating Parent Item so to associate parent item under any merchant consignment, updating inventory item (child of a parent item based on size) so to store the Item consignment details.
- Providing restful APIs for creating merchants, merchant consignments and associating Parent items with merchant consignments.
- Script to automate creation of merchant and merchant consignment in bulk.

Store Management System

- Database updation for accommodating Store managed inventory items and orders.
- Providing restful APIs for store fulfilled orders and inventory items.
- Inventory Item blocked date changes, so that Store fulfilled inventory item can be delivered with short delay.

Buying Web Application Features

- Database updation to accommodate the new changes as per Flyrobe buy platform.
- Updating Product List, Product Detail, Shopping Cart, Coupon Calculator and Order management flow as per Flyrobe Buy Platform.
- Script to Make Clothing Items Sell Clones and Update Item Details.

International Web application

- Database updation to accommodate the new changes as per Flyrobe international buy platform.
- Updating Product List, Product Detail, Shopping Cart, Coupon Calculator and Order management flow as per Flyrobe International Buy Platform.

- Update Script to Make Sell Clones and Update Item Details.
- Optimized queries in product listing and searching.

Recommendation System

- Designing attributes for item to item mapping, so that an Item can have multiple similar styled items.
- Storing the Item and its similar items so that those can be retrieved easily.
- Checking for the availability of the item, Item with the availability will only be seen in the recommended items list API.

Data Analysis

- Analyzing Flyrobe Past order data to know the clothing categories ordered most.
- Analyzing and classifying users to insert them in respective user clusters (users who order high value clothes (high roller), users who like cool color (cool tone)).

Sentimental Analysis

- Analyzing Flyrobe Play Store review and Polarizing it with appropriate sentiment.
- Use Naive Bayes Classification to predict the incoming sentence sentiment.
- Assign classes to each review, so that it would be assigned to the appropriate team.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Python, Django, Flask, Postgresql, AngularJS, Nginx, Celery, uWSGI, Gunicorn, Android, AWS, Redis, Elasticsearch, django-rest-framework, scikit-learn, numpy, pandas.

Full Stack Developer | Shaastr | Mumbai, India

Jul 2015 – Dec 2015

Shaastr is an IIT-JEE test preparation platform for IIT coaching centers. *It offers conducting tests and evaluating the performance of the students, so that students may know on which topic they need more effort.*

- Data Modelling for Organizing and Storing Test and Results of a particular Student, Classifying Questions and Storing questions with proper tags, Data Modelling for plans available for the product (demo, gold and platinum).
- Parsing Ouestions and answers from the Document files, classifying and storing questions and its answers.
- Designing the Live test platform where students give tests and after that evaluate their performance.
- Created Server to host the staging and production platforms of the website using EC2.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Python, Django, django-rest-framework, Postgresql, AngularJS, Nginx, Celery, uWSGI, Gunicorn, cURL, AWS.

PROJECTS

Full Stack Development | Django-FCM | Open Source Project

<u>Diango-fcm</u> is a django wrapper for sending firebase cloud messages to user devices.

- Writing and analyzing the old django-gcm project and making it compatible with django rest framework and new urls of firebase cloud messaging such as the name.
- Cleaning code to keep up with newer versions of django and python.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Python, Django, django-rest-framework, Firebase Cloud Messaging API

Backend Development | FC Bayern Hackdays | Hackathon Project | https://hackdays.fcbayern.com/

ChannelZ: platform for footballers to stay fit and collaborate and compete with opponent teams.

- Writing the TCP socket backend to collect data from Arduino.
- Simulating the 3D graph from the data collected from Arduino.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Nodejs, TCP sockets.

Documenting | Pandas Documentation Spring | Open Source Project | https://python-sprints.github.io/pandas/

Pandas is an amazing library for data analysis and manipulation in python, but its documentation needs to be more clear and precise for the reference and leverage the power of pandas.

- Contributed from Mumbai chapter (https://github.com/pandas-dev/pandas/pull/20128).
- <u>Technologies</u>: Python, Pandas.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Applications DAVV-IIPS Indore, India (CGPA 7.86/10)	2009 – 2012
Master of Computer Applications DAVV-IIPS Indore, India (CGPA 8.23/10)	2012 – 2015

CERTIFICATIONS

- Power Searching with Google (Google courses: powersearchingwithgoogle.com).
- Intro to Computer Science CS101 (Udacity.com).
- Learn to Program: The fundamentals (University of Toronto ,Coursera.org).
- Design and Analysis of Algorithms Part I (Stanford University, Coursera.org).
- Startup Engineering (Stanford University, Coursera.org).
- Making sense with Data (Google Courses: datasense.withgoogle.com/course).
- Interactive Programming with Python Part I (Rice University, Coursera.org).
- Introduction to Python for Data Science (Filip Schouwenaars, DataCamp.com).
- Ethical Hacking Learning Path at Linkedin Learning.
- Data Science Learning Path at Linkedin Learning.
- Blockchain Basics at Linkedin Learning.

CONFERENCES AND HACKATHONS

PyCon 2013 - Nimhans convention center, Bangalore, India.	2013
SciPy 2013 - IIT Bombay, Mumbai, India	2013
IEEE Intellect Conference Education Workshop 2015, Mumbai, India	2015
AWS Innovate 2016 Mumbai, India	2016
PyCon 2016 - JNU Delhi, India	2016
SciPy 2016 - IIT Bombay, Mumbai, India	2016
AWS Innovate 2017 Mumbai, India	2017
SciPy 2017 - IIT Bombay, Mumbai, India	2017
FC Bayern Hackdays - Allianz Arena, Munich Germany	2018
Pandas Documentation Sprint (PyData Mumbai)	2018

PROFILES

Personal Website: http://chitrank-dixit.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chitrank-dixit-03200555/

Github: https://github.com/Chitrank-Dixit

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/1433639/chitrank-dixit

Blog: http://trackleech.blogspot.com/

Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/user/chitrankdixit